<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: octopress | Anuvind Venu Menon]]></title>
  <link href="http://manuvind.github.io/blog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://manuvind.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-27T22:11:02-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://manuvind.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anuvind Venu Menon]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://manuvind.github.io/blog/2013/12/27/first-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-27T19:56:19-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://manuvind.github.io/blog/2013/12/27/first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following the archetype layed out before me I have chosen the ubiquitous title of &ldquo;First Post&rdquo; for my first blog post. Now never having written a blog before I am unsure of the writing style I should follow or how I should structure these things. Bearing this in my mind I guess I should start with giving credit where credit is due.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The creation of this blog/personal website occurred thanks largely to the opensource blogging framework <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> built by Brandon Mathis on top of <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>, the blog aware static site generator. I chose Octopress primarily due to it&rsquo;s ease of use in generating blog posts and pages with given css and javascripts. So I can focus mostly on content and if need be tweak the look of the site further down the road. Also, I like jekyll&rsquo;s philosophy of creating a static site with necessary html, css, and javascript pages, since I believe anything more for a personal website is a bit too much.</p>

<p>Furthermore, this site utilizes the <a href="https://github.com/macjasp/cleanpress">cleanpress</a> Octopress theme built by <a href="https://github.com/macjasp">macjasp</a>. I made use of this theme due the clean form factor and design that it employed. Also, I feel that this style naturally focuses the user on the content which should be the focus of this personal website/blog.</p>

<p>Alright, I think I have gotten enough experience with <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax">markdown</a> for now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
